<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Ben Unsworth</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/"/>
 <updated>2025-07-28T17:36:28+01:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Ben Unsworth</name>
   <email>ben.unsworth1+blog@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Weeknotes 21st to 27th July</title>
   <link href="/2025/07/27/weeknotes-july-27/"/>
   <updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>/2025/07/27/weeknotes-july-27</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jukesie’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalbydefault.com/2025/06/15/my-nostalgia-act-era/&quot;&gt;Nostalgia Act Era&lt;/a&gt; has been a good kick up the backside for my stop-start relationship with blogging. Or at least personal blogging and writing things down on the internet under my own website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weeknotes are a great way to get back into the habit. Giles Turnbull has written down &lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org/doingweeknotes/index.html&quot;&gt;what they are, how they work and how to start your own&lt;/a&gt;. A few of the folks whose notes I read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.annkempster.com/&quot;&gt;Ann Kempster&lt;/a&gt; - delivery, strategy, gardening, Wales&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://neilojwilliams.net/&quot;&gt;Neil Williams&lt;/a&gt; - ex-GOV.UK, now at BFI, internet, culture, Crystal Palace&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sharonodea.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Sharon O’Dea&lt;/a&gt; - digital, workplace, employee experience, comms, Amsterdam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://benholliday.com/&quot;&gt;Ben Holliday&lt;/a&gt; - 20 years of blog posts on design adn digital&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mattedgar.com/&quot;&gt;Matt Edgar&lt;/a&gt; - Digital and Design in the NHS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-ive-been-doing&quot;&gt;What I’ve been doing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handing over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m moving on from TPXimpact. I’ve got about two weeks left and have mostly handed over to a colleague. I’ve found the right job in the right place (more on this in a week or so), so leaving a little earlier than planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the work with one of our major new clients in a good spot. The teams are happy, delivering well and we can see how the work will make a real impact on outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit of admin writing new statements of work before I sign off and give back the laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-need-to-take-care-of&quot;&gt;What I need to take care of&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly life admin. Off to France in two weeks time, passports have all just arrived (gotta love the excellent and FAST passports service).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing all the jobs in the house to get it ready to sell. New job will mean moving back to South West London / Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-ive-been-inspired-by&quot;&gt;What I’ve been inspired by&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juksie and the associated buzz around the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalbydefault.com/2025/07/03/camp-digital-2025-working-in-the-open/&quot;&gt;power, peril and privilege of working in the open.&lt;/a&gt; It was enough to get me past playing with static site generators (you can read about this on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://benunsworth.co.uk/about/&quot;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt;page) and posting content.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Schwellenangst</title>
   <link href="/2025/07/25/first-post/"/>
   <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>/2025/07/25/first-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Schwellenangst. A German term for the fear of crossing a threshold and trying something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first post on a new blog is mostly about just starting. I’ve spent a lot of the last 15+ years creating the conditions for teams to think out loud and work in the open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve not great at consistently doing this myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been periods where I’ve strung together a series of posts about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/buckinghamshire-digital-service/buckinghamshire-council-website-weeknote-20-69a77878fd19&quot;&gt;leading a team building digital services for a new unitary council&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@benunsworth/the-12-week-sub-10-in-10-hours-training-plan-140c594b66f9&quot;&gt;getting back into triathlon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My magnum opus was a post about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@benunsworth/building-a-shed-you-can-work-from-home-in-acd45621abdf&quot;&gt;building a shed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few things have happened to make me post this &lt;a href=&quot;https://wrd.as.uky.edu/sites/default/files/1-Shitty%20First%20Drafts.pdf&quot;&gt;shitty first draft&lt;/a&gt; on the internet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new job, back in the public sector, starting at the end of August&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jukesie’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalbydefault.com/2025/06/15/my-nostalgia-act-era/&quot;&gt;nostalgia act era&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Rm8jZJWSvNM?feature=shared&quot;&gt;recent talk at Camp Digital: The power, peril and privilege of working in the open&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other people’s posts continue to be a source of fun, help and inspiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
